Guide to the Stanford Technology Ventures Program, Entrepreneurial Thought Leaders Seminar, Videorecordings SC1209
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 2001-2014
  - Suster, Mark, Start on Your Own, 2010-10-14; 2521; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Serial entrepreneur and investor Suster, Mark urges founders to start out on their own, to avoid early dilution. Suster believes entrepreneurs deserve to keep a greater share of their companies, when possible, as they are the ones taking the critical first leap. While Suster claims some in Silicon Valley may think this idea is "heresy," he does not understand why burgeoning entrepreneurs are willing to give so much away, so early.
  - Suster, Mark, The Co-Founder Mythology, 2010-10-14; 2522; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    While many legendary Silicon Valley companies were founded by teams of two, partnerships aren't without their problems, states venture capitalist Suster, Mark. Disagreements arise based on personal life changes, business strategies, and roles within the company. Suster prefers to avoid playing the role of co-founder "marriage counselor" by working with a strong, individual entrepreneur.
  - Suster, Mark, Make Tech Part of Your DNA, 2010-10-14; 2523; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    No Internet or tech company should launch without having in-house technical manpower to build the product, says serial entrepreneur Suster, Mark. While business savvy on the founding team is important, those skills need to be balanced with a sturdy base of engineering, programming, or other technical know-how. Additionally, a company makes itself more attractive to funding and acquisition if it has intrinsic technical expertise.
  - Suster, Mark, Don't Raise Too Much Capital, 2010-10-14; 2524; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Too much money can be a bad thing for a growing business, says Suster, Mark, serial entrepreneur. With large sums comes great expectations, and investors will expect quick movement and fast returns. Additionally, large investments can inhibit options when it comes to making a preferred exit decision.
  - Suster, Mark, Lean Startups and Fat Startups, 2010-10-14; 2525; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Venture capitalist Suster, Mark believes being a lean startup is related to size and funding levels, rather than speed and product iteration. However, once a startup finds a strong product and market fit, they will need to get "fat" quickly, in order to compete with larger companies, particularly in "winner take most" markets.
  - Suster, Mark, Branding and Commitment, 2010-10-14; 2526; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Serial entrepreneur Suster, Mark offers quick lessons in smart branding for startups: 1) Your company name should be your URL address, 2) Don't let your company name box you in, and 3) Be careful of using words in your name that mean something else. Suster also explains why you should have the commitment to see your startup through.
  - Suster, Mark, Relationships with Angels and Venture Capitalists, 2010-10-14; 2527; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Raising venture capital is worse than marriage, says investor and serial entrepreneur Suster, Mark, noting that you can at least get divorced when it comes to marriage. Suster expresses surprise that a startup team would be willing to accept a funding partnership, without taking the time to truly get to know the angel or VC. This business relationship is long, intimate, and permanent, so both parties should carefully choose their partners.
  - Suster, Mark, How to Access Investors, 2010-10-14; 2528; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Venture capitalist and entrepreneur Suster, Mark shares insights on how startups can connect with investors. He explains the best method is to access investors through other entrepreneurs. Suster speaks to the need for a startup to find their first anchor investor, whose presence can often cause additional funding sources to come forward.
  - Suster, Mark, Measuring a Venture Capitalist's Success, 2010-10-14; 2529; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Which metrics indicate whether a venture capitalist is performing well? It's more than simple ROI. Venture capitalist Suster, Mark speaks of the three career phases to examine: 1) Building a pipeline of deals, 2) Nurturing your portfolio companies, and 3) Harvesting investments and obtaining exits. He states that success in venture capital takes about a decade to determine.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Leadership and Disruptive Technologies (Entire Talk), 2010-10-21; 2530; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Prescott, Thomas, CEO of medical device manufacturer Align Technology, discusses disruptive product innovation and leadership in the medical device industry. Prescott shares the company's story, including insights on the launch of their signature product, the Invisalign orthodontic system. He also discusses operational trends and the need for sound analysis of financing, product execution, and business development tactics.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Technology Benefits from Operations, 2010-10-21; 2531; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Despite being a self-professed failure as an entrepreneur, Prescott, Thomas, CEO of med-tech firm Align Technology, points out the value of having a solid operations person at a growing start-up. According to Prescott, first-to-market entrepreneurs face great challenges to capture market share, and an effective operator can help build healthy growth.
  - Prescott, Thomas, From Funding to Product Launch, 2010-10-21; 2532; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Align Technology CEO Prescott, Thomas discusses the financing history of the company from its inception to initial product launch. Prescott points out a historical difference indicative of the roaring 1990's - namely, $280 million in financing before the company turned a profit. Today, virtual product models and increased pressure on profitability would make this heavy financial front-loading difficult to achieve.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Balancing the Founder/Operator Relationship, 2010-10-21; 2533; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Maturity is the basis for a complimentary relationship between a new operations person and founders, says Align Technology CEO Prescott, Thomas. Both parties need to respect one another's strongest skills, assets, and objectives, and keep the health of the company as the overarching goal. Additionally, it's a good idea for both founder and operator to consider when they, too, will need to be replaced by those with better skills to achieve new levels of scale.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Marketing Medical Technologies, 2010-10-21; 2534; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    When introducing a new medical device such as "invisible" orthodontics, it can be a struggle to bring the medical community on board. Align Technology CEO Prescott, Thomas discusses the necessity of clinical research documentation and sales and marketing materials targeting both patients and practitioners as essential tools for product push. Prescott points out introducing new devices is particularly challenging when the technology does not improve patient mortality.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Gaps of Opportunity in Technology, 2010-10-21; 2535; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Where should entrepreneurs in the field of medical technology be casting their nets? Prescott, Thomas, the CEO of Align Technology with years of experience in med-tech operations, points toward cardiac health, cancer, pulmonary disease, and type-2 diabetes as lucrative problems for med-tech to solve. Prescott also discusses opportunities in informatics, genetic profiling, and the convergence between medical device engineering and medical professionals.
  - Prescott, Thomas, No Patience for Profitability, 2010-10-21; 2536; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Before you create a revolution via a business launch, have an idea of how you're going to build an enterprise and capture profit, says Prescott, Thomas, CEO of Align Technology. He quotes Clayton Christensen who advises entrepreneurs to, "Be patient for growth; don't be patient for profitability." Know from the onset how the company can be scaled and how it will be exited. Prescott says this is the difference between a company with longevity and one with simply an interesting product.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Everything Starts with the Right Team, 2010-10-21; 2537; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Prescott, Thomas, CEO of Align Technology, used to believe a company was launched with a good idea and then a team was assembled to bring that idea to fruition. He now feels strongly that an "A" team must first be assembled, and then brilliance will roll out from their collaboration. Everything starts with having the right team around the table, and that team - including yourself - will always be evolving.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Love the Journey, 2010-10-21; 2538; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    If the journey on your career path is enjoyable, then you will emerge satisfied and successful, advises CEO Prescott, Thomas. However, if one works simply to secure stock options, wealth, or position - then the course needs severe correction.
  - Prescott, Thomas, Maintain a Healthy Paranoia, 2010-10-21; 2539; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Align Technology CEO Prescott, Thomas urges entrepreneurs, particularly those operating as small fish amidst sharks, to keep asking themselves what someone else working in the field would have to do to out-innovate or out-perform your best efforts. Always know the answer to this question: "How can someone else satisfy your customer better?"
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Funding Thunder Lizard Entrepreneurs [Entire Talk], 2010-10-27; 2540; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Stanford Engineering lecturer and FLOODGATE partner Miura-Ko, Ann offers insight into the democratization of innovation in the Internet age, and its affect on investment cycles. Additionally, Miura-Ko speaks candidly about the need to test business models, her firm's desire to be an advocate for "thunder lizard" entrepreneurs, and the challenges of achieving true work/life balance.
  - Hsieh, Tony, Startup Growing Pains, 2010-10-11; 2541; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Zappos.com CEO Hsieh, Tony discusses his reasoning behind selling his company, LinkExchange, to Microsoft. Hsieh explains how working at a startup remained fun, based on hiring passionate friends. However, after reaching the 20-employee mark, startup growing pains made selling a good idea.
  - Hsieh, Tony, Culture is Priority One, 2010-10-11; 2542; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    CEO Hsieh, Tony shares why culture is priority number one at his company, Zappos.com. His secret is that by investing resources in the company's cultural commitment to customer service, the deeply satisfied customers then do the valuable word-of-mouth marketing.
  - Hsieh, Tony, Core Values of Culture, 2010-10-11; 2543; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Hsieh, Tony, CEO of Zappos.com, reviews the company's core values of culture. Hsieh explains living by (and hiring for) these core values creates an authentic company culture within Zappos.com. These values took over a year to develop, and are revisited annually through the insights and reflections of all employees.
  - Hsieh, Tony, Chase the Vision, 2010-10-11; 2544; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Zappos.com CEO Hsieh, Tony frequently speaks at entrepreneurship events, where audience members often ask him what business opportunities will make them rich. Hsieh encourages entrepreneurs to chase their vision, rather than money. Entrepreneurs should choose something they would be happy doing for the next 10 years.
  - Hsieh, Tony, Frameworks of Happiness, 2010-10-11; 2545; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Zappos.com CEO Hsieh, Tony is passionate about positive emotions and outcomes for employees, vendors, and customers. This interest led him to study the science of happiness. In this clip, Hsieh shares some of his key findings related to finding and delivering happiness.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, The Internet is Under-Hyped, 2010-10-27; 2546; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    We talk about the Internet as a series of tools, says FLOODGATE Fund partner Miura-Ko, Ann, but we are too quick to dismiss its influence on history, and how our history will be written. Miura-Ko cites how the Internet democratizes our ability to innovate, and how these innovations will come to be seen as having impacts on the level of those made by the Ford Model T and the Gutenberg press.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, The Collapsing Cost of Product Building, 2010-10-27; 2547; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Price drops in mass market technology, open-source software, crowd-sourcing, and cloud computing have vastly reduced the costs necessary to build new products in the Internet age. In this clip, FLOODGATE Fund co-founding partner Miura-Ko, Ann points out how these elements have converged to create rapid prototyping flexibility, and a never-before-seen ease and ability to tailor new products to market.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Rapid Business Model Testing, 2010-10-27; 2548; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    A successful startup does not flower solely from a great product or idea, says Miura-Ko, Ann, partner at FLOODGATE Fund. She argues that success stems from the ability to grow a business around that great idea. The venture ecosystem, a flush customer base, accessible distribution channels and manufacturing - all of these factors must converge into a business model that is both viable and scalable. Fortunately, the Internet allows companies to rapidly test business models, for example, through the use of social media leveraged with demand creation and flexible pricing structures.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Running Out of Iterations, 2010-10-27; 2549; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The lean startup operates with a business plan that can reshape until a successful business model develops. By quickly pivoting based on market feedback, a company can extend their runway without additional dilution from raising greater amounts of capital, according to FLOODGATE Fund partner Miura-Ko, Ann. She explains entrepreneurs can then make dollars last longer, which allows for an increase in possible product iterations. In today's business climate, Miura-Ko states, an entrepreneur never wants to run our of chances to iterate.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Investing in Thunder Lizards, 2010-10-27; 2550; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    In this colorful clip, FLOODGATE Fund co-founder Miura-Ko, Ann describes the ideal venture to invest in: one whose team and ambition closely resembles Godzilla. They are huge, hungry, and spawn from "radioactive", best-in-class technology DNA. These companies emerge on the scene with an attitude, and have the passion to devour a market at will.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Lean Does Not Mean "Small", 2010-10-27; 2551; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The amount of capital that you take in has nothing to do with the size of a company's ambitions, says Miura-Ko, Ann, co-founding partner at FLOODGATE. Historically, some of today's largest technology brands, such as Ebay, Microsoft, Apple, raised relatively low amounts of capital early on. Smart business models, data, and vision steer a company, regardless of its size, to scale sensibly and remain capital efficient.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Business Models Matter, 2010-10-27; 2552; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    FLOODGATE Fund co-founding partner Miura-Ko, Ann believes it's the business model that matters most, rather than the business plan. A well-thought out business model that is data-driven and scenario-focused will be seriously considered. According to Miura-Ko, models do a better job of unearthing assumptions about a company's users, customers, pricing, demand creation, sales channels, supply chain, and overall logistics - all critical components to building a successful venture.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, Is Work/Life Balance Possible?, 2010-10-27; 2553; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The myth of work/life balance, says FLOODGATE Fund partner Miura-Ko, Ann, is that one can actually strike a balance. As a mother of two, she advises anyone with a family, who also seeks to carve a path in entrepreneurship, to recognize that it is a struggle to achieve balance. Knowing how much time and energy a new venture can demand, she states the importance of feeling passion for your business mission. Only a great venture will make taking time away from family feel like a worthy trade-off.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, The Importance of a Technical Co-founder, 2010-10-27; 2554; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    In this clip, FLOODGATE Fund partner Miura-Ko, Ann discusses the importance of technical expertise intrinsic to a startup team. Miura-Ko states it is necessary to have this knowledge onboard and in-house, whenever possible. However, she has witnessed incidences of skilled technical managers who have successfully outsourced their engineering needs, though she notes this is an exception to the rule.
  - Miura-Ko, Ann, The Entrepreneurship of Venture Capital, 2010-10-27; 2555; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Miura-Ko, Ann shares the origin story of FLOODGATE Fund, where she is a co-founding partner with angel investor Mike Maples. In this poignant clip, Miura-Ko shares how she decided to step into investing when she saw that FLOODGATE could make a meaningful and innovative impact on the venture capital industry. Miura-Ko also shares some important value-driven moments from her career, and her ingrained need to be world class at every possible turn.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Customer Focus Builds Global Growth [Entire Talk], 2010-11-03; 2556; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Piacentini, Diego, Senior VP of International Retail for Amazon, discusses the company's growth-centered business model, its global presence, and the strides it takes to sustain a successful customer experience. Piacentini also describes Amazon's innovative approaches to operations, mergers and acquisitions, and labor practices.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Amazon Global Operations, 2010-11-03; 2557; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    With seven global websites and half of its revenue coming from outside North America, Amazon Senior VP of International Retail Piacentini, Diego discusses the company's global operations and strategy. The challenge, he says, is providing the same customer experience everywhere on the globe. To achieve this, Amazon utilizes a global network of call centers, fulfillment centers, and websites that cater to regional customers.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Work Backwards from the Customer, 2010-11-03; 2558; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Stick to a vision and the company shall succeed, advises Amazon Senior VP Piacentini, Diego. For Amazon this means adhering to founder Jeff Bezos' original vision: Build a site where users can find anything they want to buy at the lowest price. To achieve this vision, Piacentini highlights Amazon's dedication to building all code in-house, and safety measures to validate customer purchases.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Adhere to Core Values, 2010-11-03; 2559; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Piacentini, Diego, Amazon Senior VP, talks about the value of a company adhering to its own code, even when it comes to honoring a lower price point. Piacentini shares an anecdote about returning money to Chinese customers after a bestselling book dropped in price. The result, he states, was gaining unprecedented customer loyalty and a tremendous marketing boost.
  - Piacentini, Diego, The Myth of Best Practices, 2010-11-03; 2560; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    For Amazon, all operations are equal until proven - with data - that they need to be changed. For example, in China, it became apparent that Amazon had to invest in delivery systems for the last mile - which often means bicycle delivery. This unique need also mandated software for customers to schedule an exact delivery time, and for delivery staff to process payments. Amazon Senior VP Diego Pacentini uses this as an example of how the company adapts to its environment while still adhering to its core vision.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Maximize Experimentation, 2010-11-03; 2561; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Amazon offers its employees the "Just Do It" award, a fun recognition with an old Nike shoe, that is handed to anyone who implements a smart idea or innovation outside of their normal job tasks. Amazon is built to tolerate mistakes, says Senior VP of International Retail Piacentini, Diego - provided those mistakes don't get repeated.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Take Risks Outside Your Core Business, 2010-11-03; 2562; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Amazon Senior VP Piacentini, Diego discusses how Amazon Web Services (AWS) was born. He discusses how the retailer decided to take a risk and move away from its core competency, build APIs, and rent out server space during slower retail months. Piacentini also talks about how other online giants have now followed Amazon's lead.
  - Piacentini, Diego, Don't Fall in Love with Being Number One, 2010-11-03; 2563; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The largest difficulty of running the top online retail brand is the diligent work required not to appear arrogant. Piacentini, Diego, Amazon's Senior VP of International Retail, states that his company's greatest challenge is how to appear humble in the eyes of the customer, and to constantly innovate and improve.
  - Sutton, Bob, What Great Leaders Do [Entire Talk], 2010-11-10; 2564; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    In this lecture that parallels his book Good Boss, Bad Boss, Stanford professor Sutton, Bob unpacks the best habits of beloved and effective managers, and details the worst habits of those who fail to lead. The best leaders develop and nurture those who work for them. However, when bosses gain more power, they can easily grow oblivious to the needs of those they lead.
  - Sutton, Bob, Listen to Those You Lead, 2010-11-10; 2565; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Bestselling author and Stanford professor Sutton, Bob offers insights from his book, Good Boss, Bad Boss. Two important points: 1) Individuals in a position of authority will be under intense scrutiny from those they manage; and 2) Leaders receive disproportionally more blame and more credit for organizational performance. Sutton shares some surprising statistics related to this point, and explains that the best bosses work hard to remain in-tune with those they manage.
  - Sutton, Bob, The Toxic Tandem, 2010-11-10; 2566; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Stanford Professor Sutton, Bob discusses the "toxic tandem," which he defines as when bosses do not pay attention to their employees, while still being closely watched by those same employees. This asymmetry of attention can be devastating, and in this clip, Sutton shares an anecdote of one company team who anticipated layoffs just by reading their boss' unconscious behavior.
  - Sutton, Bob, Power Poisoning, 2010-11-10; 2567; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    According to author Sutton, Bob, when someone is placed in a position of power, three things can happen to cause "power poisoning": 1) The individual focuses on their own needs and concerns; 2) The individual focuses little attention on the needs of others; and 3) The individual often acts like the rules don't apply to them. Evidence is also mounting, says Sutton, that the more successful a manager is, the more likely they are to break the rules.
  - Sutton, Bob, Hallmarks of Great Bosses, 2010-11-10; 2568; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Stanford professor and author Sutton, Bob covers a number of hallmarks and strategies of smart, in-tune bosses. While traditional management theory dictates constant monitoring of employees and processes, this may not be the best tactic, says Sutton. His research reports this is particularly true for bosses managing creative teams and employees. In these situations, over-management can backfire, often stifling creativity and innovation.
  - Sutton, Bob, Listening for the Truth, 2010-11-10; 2569; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)